# Josh Cesana

joshuacesana@gmail.com | 925-200-3164 | San Ramon, CA | github.com/joshcesana | linkedin.com/in/joshcesana

#### **SUMMARY**

Motivated full stack web developer with experience creating custom websites using JavaScript (React), Ruby on Rails, HTML, and CSS. Organized and focused with a strong passion to continuously learn new technologies. Former Operations Manager experienced working in teams with strong attention to detail.

#### **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

Flatiron School, Online Coding Bootcamp Full Stack Web Development May 2018 - January 2019

## React News - React, Redux, HTML, CSS Video Github

News client for searching, viewing, and saving articles.

- Implemented create-react-app, Redux middleware with a Rails API backend
- Styled with MaterializeCSS framework
- Dynamic routing with react-router
- Fetched data from newsapi.org API
- Designed database schema using ActiveRecord

# Rails Recipes - Rails, JavaScript, HTML, CSS Video Github

Recipes client for creating, viewing, updating, and deleting recipes.

- Designed client side with Bulma and custom CSS
- Built API functionality using Ruby on Rails and MVC pattern
- Implemented Devise for user authentication
- Implemented Active Storage for image attachment
- Implemented cocoon for added form functionality

## Task Buddy - Ruby, Sinatra, HTML, CSS Video Github

To do list client for adding and deleting tasks.

- Built database schema and configured ActiveRecord associations
- Built RESTful APIs using Sinatra framework and Rake tasks
- Used Bcrypt for secure password storage

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript | HTML5 | CSS | Ruby | SQL

Frameworks: React | Redux | Node | Rails | Sinatra | Bootstrap | Bulma | MaterializeCSS

Tools: Atom | Sublime | Git | Photoshop

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# **Operations Manager**

February 2016 - May 2018

Piace Carta, LLC

- Oversaw the creation and implementation of online retail website
- Trained and supported staff
- Monitored product inventory

# **Business Owner - Self Employed**

May 2013 - February 2016

Lifebox Cases, LLC

- Exceeded \$1,000,000 in sales
- Managed A/P, A/R, billing, purchasing, cost analysis, marketing research, and taxes
- Hired, trained, and supervised new team members

## **Web Application Developer**

May 2011 - May 2013

Global Logistics Village, Inc.

- Enhanced user interface for large scale online service
- Experienced positive exposure to working with development team in collaborative environment
- Acquired valuable technical skills, strengthening attention to detail

#### **Sales Coordinator**

December 2007 - May 2011

Global Logistics Village, Inc.

- Contacted executive level members at target corporations
- Identified needs of target corporations
- Proposed solutions with custom logistics system

# **Loan Officer**

December 2006 - December 2007

Home 123, Inc.

- Secured Top Closer Award (by monthly volume)
- Originated new customer loans through networking, leads, and cold calling
- Coordinated with clients, managers, underwriters, and appraisers in the delivery of loans

### **Staff Accountant**

May 2005 - December 2006

KSJG, LLP

- Started, assisted, and completed audit reports
- Assisted in the audit of organizations from various industries
- Coordinated data collection, workflow, and time management with clients

## **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** 

May 2018 - January 2019

Full Stack Web Development Online Bootcamp

**Biola University** 

August 2000 - May 2004

BS in Business - Accounting

### **INTERESTS**

Cycling, Basketball, Live Symphony Concerts, Crosswords